classcreator.com 2018-12-21

# Class Creator Privacy Policy

**Last modified: November 30, 2012 (view archived versions)**

Our Privacy Policy explains:

  * What information we collect and why we collect it.
  * How we use that information.
  * The choices we offer, including how to access and update information.

We've tried to keep it as simple as possible, but if you're not familiar with terms like cookies, IP addresses and browsers, then read about these key terms first.

## Information We Collect

We collect information in two ways:

  * **Information you give us when creating a website, or when joining an existing website.** When you do either of these, we'll ask for personal information, like your name, email address, telephone number and date of birth. We'll then create a Member Profile, which may include your name and photo. The part of your profile containing your email address, physical address, and phone numbers is not visible to anyone except the administrators of the website. The rest of the profile information you supply including birth date is only visible to other persons who are logged into the same website. The only exception to this is City of Residence, which may be seen by a non-logged in viewer in the Where We Live feature. You can override the sharing limitations, but the default settings are the most protective of your privacy. 
  * **Information we get from your use of our services (server logs). We may collect information about the services that you use and how you use them, like when you visit the website, and details of your activity on each page. This information includes:**
    * your hardware model, operating system version, and web browser version.
    * the Internet protocol address from which you are connecting to the internet.
    * event information such as browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL.
    * cookies that may uniquely identify your browser and/or collect and store information necessary to provide the services you are using.

## How we use information we collect

We use the information we collect from all of our services to provide, maintain, protect and improve them, to develop new ones, and to protect us and our users.

## Information we share

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations and individuals unless one of the following circumstances apply:

  * **With your consent**

We may share personal profile information via publicly accessible pages of your website when we have your consent to do so. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any personal profile information.

  * **For external processing**

We may provide personal information to trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. For instance, information provided through our Reunion Planner may be used to facilitate ACH direct deposit transactions on your behalf. We do not provide personal information to others without your agreement to do so.

  * **For legal reasons**

We may share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

    * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
    * enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.
    * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.
    * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of us, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of our services.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information and give affected users notice before personal information is transferred or becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

## Information security

We work hard to protect our systems and our users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information we hold. In particular:

  * We encrypt credit card payment services using SSL.
  * We review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems.
  * We restrict access to personal information to persons who need to know that information in order to process it for us in order to provide you the service we offer.
  * You can elect to block the public and search engines from accessing information you add to your personal Profile page. All logged in fellow site members can see all information you add to your personal Profile page. In rare cases a site member may join under false pretenses and claim to be somebody they are not (i.e. an imposter). Class Creator provides Class Administrators tools to combat this such as a New Member Verification feature. Class Creator does not require the use of the Verification feature nor can we assure proper use of the Verification feature when it is enabled. Therefore in rare cases a member can pose as somebody they are not. If you use this site you acknowledge the possibility of somebody joining the site under an assumed or false identity. Because of this infrequent but real possibility you should not post personal information or photos on your Profile page you do not want non members to see even if you have blocked search engines and the public from accessing your Profile information.

## Advertising placed on Free (ads) sites:

### The DoubleClick cookie

The [DoubleClick cookie](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090) is used by Google in the ads served on the websites of its partners, such as websites displaying AdSense ads or participating in Google certified ad networks. When users visit a partner's website and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on that end user's browser.

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website.
  * Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). (Alternatively, you can direct users to opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).)

If you have not [opted out of third-party ad serving](https://www.google.com/support/dfp_sb/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=94152), the cookies of other [third-party vendors or ad networks](https://www.google.com/support/dfp_sb/bin/answer.py?answer=94149) may also be used to serve ads to you on your site. 

## Enforcement

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy. If we receive formal written complaints we will contact the person who made the complaint to follow up. We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that we cannot resolve with our users directly.

## Changes

Our Privacy Policy may change periodically. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of privacy policy changes). We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review.

## Questions Regarding Privacy

For more information about Privacy and Security issues please read [_Questions About Passwords and Privacy_](http://www.classcreator.com/faqs.cfm#privacy) in our FAQ section.

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, our privacy practices, or your dealings with us, please contact us in writing at:

Class Creator  
2500 Packard St.  
Suite 204  
Ann Arbor, MI 48104
